Ernesto Albarez

Address

French 2849 - Recoleta - CABA

Cellphone

11-2250-0981

Email

ernesto.albarez@protonmail.com

Date of birth

May 2nd, 1993

DNI

37.689.195

Cuil/Cuit

20-37689195-0



Summary

I'm a QA analyst experienced working with remote teams, most of them based on the USA. I've led manual and automation regression testing, reporting bugs, testing of new features and also managing the automation test suite both backend and frontend. Currently I am improving my automation skills

Experience

GlobalLogic Argentina

March 2019 - Current

Client: local e-wallet

Ssr QA analyst - head of backed testing: working with scrum methodology, testing the new services for the features developed during the sprint and preparing to automate it for the next sprint. I'm also doing some regression and reporting bugs. The team is all remote and we're working alongside the development team. Documentation and bug logging with JIRA.

Client: e-learning webpage

Ssr QA automation: write new automation test flows for the platform, worked with a remote based on Washington, following a Kanban methodology. Worked with Cucumber + Ruby + Capybara + Selenium technologies. Also fixed the test from previous regressions. Also worked on getting the mostAPI testing coverage in order to simplify the UI test scenarios. Documentation and bug logging with JIRA.

Client: cloud services company

Ssr QA automation: test cases scenario analysis for automation, automated test cases writing and updates in Python + selenium. Worked with a remote team from San Francisco following the Scrum methodology to estimate release work and keep the automation regression testing suite updated. Documentation and bug logging with JIRA.

Hexacta Argentina

May 2018 - March 2019

Client: work insurance company

Ssr QA: manual test cases scenarios analysis, test cases creation and updates. Worked with a remote team from Portland taking information about new features during the meetings with the client. Then having meetings with the developers and creating the test plan in order to validate scenarios and integration. Documentation and bug logging with TFS, a microsoft software.

Valtech Argentina

December 2017 - May 2018

QA automation engineer: had training in backend automation technologies and GitHub for a future client, the company couldn't concrete the project contract and I had to move on to the next job opportunity.

AppDirect Argentina

September 2016 - December 2017

Internal development company team

QA analyst: head of manual regression testing, follow up of the release and creation of reports for the hole team. In addition, I validated some of the future functionalities on QA environment (backend, frontend and database validation). Worked with a remote team from San Francisco. JIRA was the tool to documentate and log bugs, tasks and working hours. TestRial to write and update test cases, and for the regressions. Jenkins to run the automated test cases and get information for the reports.

Accenture Argentina

July 2014 - August 2016

Internal financial company team

Manual regression testing, bug reporting and validation after fixing. Worked with developers from India. All the tools for test regression and reporting were developed internally.

Client: local petrol company

Analysis, development and testing of SAP implementation ECC IS-OL. Redaction of functional documentation, UML flow diagrams. Worked with local teams only of PM, PP, QM and FI SAP modules. Used ARIS and SOLMAN tools.

Education

National University of La Matanza - Systems engineering

I haven't finished my studies yet, planning start again

Extra academic

SAP FI-CO - Accenture Argentina

July 2014 - August 2014

Introduction to ERP, FI-CO modules, customization, use of SAP transactions, classification of SAP transactions, introduction of financials, generation of invoices, reports and custom reports

Java workshop

April 2016 - July 2016

Classes, objects, methods, encapsulation, polymorphism, composition, concurrency, persistency.

MySQL workshop

July 2017 - September 2017

Operator, primary key, data types, default values, auto-calculated values, logic operators, duplicated data, erase, tables rename, table creation, insert from other tables, update from other tables.

Selenium workshop

May 2017 - December 2017

Selenium WebDriver, HTML selectors, selenium locators, run scripts, run multiple test cases in one single script, debugging.

Languages

- English: I can speak fluently and write. I'm used to work with teams based on the USA
- **Portuguese**: I was born on the border near Brazil, so I'm used to speak but I cannot write
- Italian: beginner, just learning it for fun